# **Gian Riyanto**

Software Engineer

+61 406 073 200 li.griyanto@gmail.com U.S. Permanent Resident

#### **Profile**

Software engineer with a strong passion for products, people, and building delightful user experiences. Driven by my intellectual curiosity and strong growth-mindset, I enjoy the process of collaboratively transforming new learnings into meaningful contributions through code, software design, and products.

#### **Personal Links**

gianriyanto.com github.com/gianriyanto linkedin.com/in/riyantogian

# **Experience**

## **Software Engineer**

HelloFresh Jan 2021 - Present

- Built and delivered product features and services to continuously improve the operations and supply chain management platform.
- Developed scalable technical solution designs with maintainable, testable, and efficient implementation that directly deliver business and user value.
- Implemented domain driven design and engineering best practices to continuously improve code base, systems, processes, and software design.

## Web Developer

Freelance Oct 2020 - Jan 2021

- Designed modern web applications to scale and transform client's business through delightful user experience solutions.
- Developed and deployed websites using Vue, Vuex, JavaScript, HTML, and pure s(css) to design UI components.
- Closely collaborated with clients to understand their business domain, process, and customer experience.

# **Software Engineer**

LinkaAja Dec 2019 - Mar 2020

- Proposed and developed automated data pipeline using Apache Airflow DAGs to orchestrate data processes and workflows.
- Built end-to-end Airflow pipelines in python to automate various business needs and use-cases.
- Collaboratively built big data infrastructure and processes to ensure data and analytics is accurate and available for all stakeholders.

# **Technology Consultant**

**HR Path** Nov 2018 - Jun 2019

- Configured SAP SuccessFactors projects based on the client's business process and requirements.
- Gathered, analysed and transformed client needs, insights and problems into tailored system solutions.

## **Education**

University of

**Technology Sydney** 

Mar 2016 - Oct 2021

B. Eng (Software) Honours

Dean's List Engineering 2021

# **Technologies**

JavaScript

Vue, Vuex

React, Hooks

HTML, CSS, SCSS

Python, PyTest

Flask, Fast API

RESTful API

PostGres

MongoDB, NoSQL

Apache Airflow

#### **Tools**

JetBrains IDE

Github, Git

AWS

Postman

JIRA. Confluence

Concourse CI

#### Skills

UI/UX Design

Domain Driven Design

Software Testing

Technology Consulting

Machine Learning

Data Analytics

Agile, Scrum

# **Software Projects**

## Consultgianti.com SPA

- Designed and developed a personal website for the founder of Aspectama, an education consulting firm.
- · Streamlined and improved efficiency of client acquisition process
- Developed a digital presence with a modern and attractive medium to engage new clients.

#### **Education Counsellor Personal Website SPA**

- Designed and developed personal websites for education counsellors - consultchen.com, consultveve.com
- Improved client acquisition process with an experience that shortens the time-to-contact.

#### I OWE YOU Web App

- Built and deployed a favours-debt-tracking web application using MERN technology stack.
- Designed UI components and developed the front-end application.
- Received an honourable mention for its UI/UX design.

### **Cryptocurrency Dashboard** Web App

- Built a live dashboard containing a collection of widgets that displays a range of data for a given cryptocurrency.
- · Developed using Vue.Js, Vuex, and Chart.Js
- Designed UI components from scratch using SCSS

#### **Teams Chat** Web App

- A team communication channel and project management platform built using ReactJS, Node, and Firebase NoSQL database.
- Collaboratively worked with a team of 15 members using Scrum and Agile practices.

#### **Analytics Dashboard** Web App

- Developed a responsive analytics dashboard for users to manage, monitor, and analyse data at a glance.
- Worked as a front-end developer designing and implementing the dashboard interface with VueJS and ChartJS.

## **Interactive Login Page** Feature

- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$  Developed a responsive and interactive login type-form feature.
- · Built using VueJS, HTML, SCSS

#### Supervised Learning Project ML Model

- Implemented a machine learning classification algorithm to predict values of a dataset.
- Employed various data analytics processes, techniques and practices using python to improve efficiency, accuracy and performance.

# Other Experiences

# Software Engineering Virtual Experience

JPMorgan Chase & Co

## **Product Analyst**

Mitra Cipta Agro

## **Programming Teacher Assistant**

Code Camp

Nov 2017 - Nov 2018

#### **Mathematics Teacher Assistant**

Montessori Mathematics Tutor

## **Relevant Coursework**

### **Core Engineering Subjects**

Design and Innovation
Business Requirements Modelling
Systems Development Methodologies
Systems Testing and Quality Management
Entrepreneurship and Commercialisation
Engineering Economics and Finance
Engineering Project Management
Mathematical Modelling

#### **Computer Science Subjects**

Advanced Internet Programming
Applications Programming
Data Structures and Algorithms
Introduction to Data Analytics
Database Fundamentals
Object-Relational Database
Software Engineering Studios (6 part course)
Software Architecture